The Second Princess is a good archer.
這二郡主好箭法呀
Her skill is not worse than yours when you were young.
不比城主當年差
Good job!
好箭法
Your Highness, you have great learning
二郡主不僅學識淵博
and you're good at Kung Fu.
武藝也精湛
The Crown Princess Election is around the corner.
少城主擢考將近
You have to practice hard.
你可要勤於習武
I hope you can become a military officer.
等日後你得了武職
I still need your support in the future.
我還有需要你幫助的地方
Trust me.
您放心
We've been friends since childhood.
我們自小一起長大
When you become the Crown Princess,
等您當上少城主
I'll do all I can to assist you.
我一定盡心輔佐
As for the Crown Princess Election,
少城主擢考
both Qianqian and I are candidates.
我和芊芊皆是候選人
It's not known who can be elected.
誰能當選 猶未可知
Just wait and see.
您就等著瞧吧
Chen Qianqian couldn't make it.
陳芊芊絕對沒戲
Don't mention this matter again.
此事不必再議
Your Highness.
三公主 三公主 三公主
Chen Qianqian!
陳芊芊
Let's have a competition.
比一場
My wound hasn't healed.
我這傷還沒好呢
When I'm fully recovered,
這等我傷好了
I'll defeat you to convince you.
我打得你心服口服的啊
When did you become so vulnerable?
你什麼時候那麼嬌弱了
It's just a joint dislocation. It must have healed already.
脫個臼到現在還沒好
You're just afraid
我看你
you'll lose, right?
就是怕輸吧
Me?
我
Yes, I am.
我就是怕輸
I won't lose if I don't compete.
不比我都不會輸
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
don't you feel ashamed?
你還有沒有點廉恥心
Stay away from Minister Pei.
離裴司學遠點
Why is she...
她怎麼
She can't...
她的武功
Chen Qianqian can't do Kung Fu anymore?
陳芊芊不會武功了
Mother, you want to see me?
母親 你召見我
Qianqian, I hear you've been diligent these days.
芊芊 聽說你最近勤勉了不少
Yes. I've been quite obedient recently.
當然 我最近真是非常聽話
I've been overcautious
謹小慎微
to avoid making trouble.
特別地乖 生怕闖禍
I hear
聽說
you've got more musicians in your mansion.
你的府上倒是添了不少的樂人
So, you want to live for enjoyment?
怎麼 最近貪玩不少
Have you forgotten that
難道你忘了
you're a princess?
你是一城郡主了嗎
Mother, you're right.
母親教訓得是
I did it wrong.
女兒知錯了
No. Mother,
不不不 母親
you misunderstood Chuchu.
你真的是誤會二姐了
It's Han Shuo
是韓爍把所有人
that sent those guys to her mansion.
送到二姐那兒去的
She knew nothing about it.
二姐真的什麼都不知道
Alright.
好了
I know you care about your sister.
我知道你們姐妹情深
Stop making excuses for her.
你就不要再替她開脫了
Your Majesty,
稟報城主
as for the Crown Princess Election,
對於少城主擢考一事
I have a suggestion.
我有一個建議
I'm wondering if I should say it out.
不知 當講不當講
Go ahead.
說來聽聽
In Huayuan City, women have the decisive say.
我花垣城向來是女子當家
Even Minister of Defense
連司軍一職
is a woman.
也是由女子擔任
The Crown Princess, as the future City Owner
而少城主是城主的繼承人
should master both civil and military skills.
更是文韜 武略 缺一不可
But over the years,
但是 這麼多年以來
only a literacy test and a discourse on politics
對於少城主的選拔
have been considered during the Crown Princess Election.
卻只有文試和策論
Your Majesty,
城主
how about letting all princesses take a Kung Fu test?
何不讓各位郡主也參加武試
A Kung Fu test?
武試
Both the Second and the Third Princesses are good at Kung Fu,
二郡主和三公主武功卓絕
especially the latter.
尤其是三公主
She has extraordinary skill.
更是身手不凡
In Huayuan,
在花垣
nobody dares to claim to be the first
她陳芊芊敢稱第二
if Chen Qianqian says she ranks second.
就沒人敢稱第一
Does everyone think
該不是所有人都覺得
I'm sure to fail in the competition
我高考無望了吧
so that they want to give me a chance to earn extra points?
為了我單加了個體育加分項
How could Lin Qi be so nice to me?
林七怎麼可能會這麼好心
The Second Princess Chen Chuchu isn't the Her Majesty's real daughter.
二郡主陳楚楚非城主親生
Chen Chuchu isn't her real daughter?
陳楚楚非城主所生
And Chen Yuanyuan is disabled.
陳沅沅又身患殘疾
So, Chen Qianqian will be
那花垣城的繼承人
the only successor of Huayuan City!
就只剩下陳芊芊一人了
If we poison Chen Qianqian,
只要我們毒殺陳芊芊
Her Majesty will certainly save her with the Dragon Bone.
城主必定拿出龍骨相救
That'll be our chance to take it,
我們趁機奪下龍骨
and your heart disease will be cured finally!
您的心疾就可以治癒了
Young Master,
少君
are you still thinking about saving your own life
您還在糾結是保您的命
or Chen Qianqian's?
還是三公主的命嗎
As for the tip-off given away,
上次密信走漏風聲一事
I've found out who's the one behind that.
我已經查到幕後之人了
Who is it?
何人
Lin Qi, how will they do the Kung Fu test?
林七 這武試怎麼安排
By giving an open challenge.
擂臺比武
Oh no. I've given myself away.
完了 我露餡了
Lin Qi has found out I couldn't do Kung Fu.
林七發現我不會武功了
No.
不不不
No way.
不行
It's unfair.
這不公平
Mother, think about it.
母親 您想啊
Everyone knows that I'm good at Kung Fu.
這所有人都知道我武功好
If a Kung Fu test is added,
專門為我增加武試
everyone will think I've pulled strings.
這明擺著走後門
It's unfair.
不公平
Mother.
母親
Qianqian,
芊芊
this is an exception we make for you.
這可是給你開設的特例
I don't expect you to win out
文試和策論
in the literacy test or about discourse on politics.
我暫且不論
But the Kung Fu test,
可這武試
you'll win, right?
你總該贏一場給我看看吧
No.
別
Don't be self-willed.
別任性
Qianqian, you're a skilled fighter.
芊芊 你武功高強
Remember to stop at where it should when you fight.
到時候點到為止
Don't get others seriously injured.
切勿傷了他人性命
What if
那要是
I'm injured by others?
別人傷了我呢
You naughty girl.
調皮
If you let others do that on purpose,
你若有心放水 輕忽怠慢
I'll give you a heavy punishment.
我定會重重地罰你
Alright. So much for today.
好了 今天就到這兒吧
No.
不
Lin Qi.
林七
Your Highness,
三公主
your mother agreed to add a Kung Fu test
城主同意增加武試
because she has placed great hopes on you.
那是對三公主寄予厚望
Don't let her down.
三公主可一定不要讓城主失望啊
Qianqian.
芊芊
Chuchu.
二姐
When Lin Qi proposed to add a Kung Fu test,
剛剛林七她提出要增加武試
why didn't you object to it?
你怎麼不站出來提反對啊
It's against you.
這對你當少城主很不利的
Mother hasn't gone far.
趁母親還沒有走遠
Let's go talk to her.
咱倆趕緊找她
Hurry.
走走走
A successor should be adept with both the pen and the sword to convince people.
少城主理應文武雙全才可服眾
It's understandable to add a Kung Fu test.
增加武試也無可厚非
If the two of us become rivals during the test,
倘若武試中你我成了敵手
don't let me win
大可將姐妹之情拋到一邊
just because I'm your sister.
萬萬不要相讓於我
I wish I could do this.
我倒也想讓讓
You're forcing a donkey to dance.
這不趕鴨子上架嗎 這不
We've been fighting since childhood.
你和我從小打到大
I'm glad we'll finally have a showdown
現在終於可以在正式場合
with each other in an impressive way.
堂堂正正地一決高下
See you on the arena.
咱們演武場上見
Life has finally decided to
生活終於對我這隻小貓咪
teach me a good lesson.
下狠手了
Your Highness.
三公主
What's up?
怎麼了
You look unhappy.
一臉不開心的樣子
No way.
不行
I have to figure out a way to avoid the Kung Fu test.
我得想個法子把武試給躲過去
Han Shuo.
韓爍
He can help me out.
韓爍可以幫我
Where did you get it?
哪裡找到的
In the backyard's kitchen.
後院廚房
The grocery guy said
雜貨鋪的夥計說
it was custom-made for Zi Rui, Chen Qianqian's servant.
是三公主的隨從梓銳定製的
He's ordered 500.
而且一下就做了五百個
All of them are piled in the backyard.
現在都堆在後院
I heard
我聽人說
Chuchu was going to catch a spy of Xuanhu City
二姐今晚要去抓玄虎城密探
and I specially went to help you out.
我特意趕過去想為你解圍
I had no idea you'd put me in that situation.
誰知道被你反擺一道
Han Shuo,
韓少君啊
I've really taken pains to help you.
你可真是辜負了我一片苦心
Why on earth did you try to save me?
三公主到底為何如此
Because I'm on your side.
因為我把你當自己人
Could it be
難道
she misled me on purpose
她有意誤導我
to gain my trust?
博取我的信任
Not only do I know your birthday date,
我不僅知道今天是你的生辰
I also know you are 186cm in height,
我還知道你身高一八六
you weigh 75 kg, your blood type is O.
七十五公斤 O型血
You like black,
喜歡黑色
don't like rainy days,
不喜歡下雨天
your favorite food is noodle soup cooked by your mom,
最喜歡吃你母親煮的清湯掛麵
you don't like ginger.
不喜歡吃薑
No wonder she knows me well.
難怪對我瞭如指掌
It turns out she has investigated me.
原來早就把我調查得一清二楚
She's making a fool of me.
將我玩弄於股掌之間
The Third Princess
三公主對韓某
is not guarded against me at all.
當真沒有半點防備
She even induced me to lower my guard.
還誘導我對她放下戒心
She's sinister and insidious.
此女子陰險狡詐
Seemingly, she was devoted to me and got me out of trouble,
表面一往情深 救我於水火
but actually, she framed me
暗地裡卻用密信
with a tip-off.
設計害我
Young Master,
少君
the doctor said
大夫叮囑過
you couldn't lose your temper.
您不能動怒啊
Chen Qianqian is just a bitch.
陳芊芊這個賤人
Young Master.
少君
Han Shuo, help me.
少君救我
I don't want to compete.
我不要比試
I don't want to do tests.
我不要考試
I don't want to be the Crown Princess.
我也不要當少城主
Is he asleep?
睡了
Your Highness.
三公主
You're asking me to save him?
這 這是要我救他
If anything happens to him,
我家少君要有個三長兩短
I won't leave it at that.
我跟你沒完
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Zi Rui.
梓銳
Go away.
起來
Han Shuo.
韓爍 韓爍
Beast!
禽獸啊
Let go of our Young Master.
你快放開我們家少君
Can't you see he's in danger?
這都什麼時候了
Go open the window wider and give him more fresh air.
去 把窗子開大一點 給他空氣
Hurry.
快點
Go open the window wider and give him more fresh air.
去把窗戶開大點 給他通氣
Han Shuo. Where is the medicine?
韓爍 藥呢
Quick-Acting Heart Reliever or Ginseng lozenge.
速效救心丸或者是人蔘含片
Anything that can save his life.
吊他命的藥呢
Medicine. Hurry up.
藥 你磨磨嘰嘰的
Here it is.
來來來
Such a big pill?
這麼大一顆
He's fainted. Do you want to choke him to death?
他都暈過去了 想噎死他嗎
Please save...
你快快
The taste...
這味
You're awake?
醒了
You're finally awake.
你終於醒了
You can't die, Han Shuo.
你可千萬不能死 韓爍
Luckily...
幸好
Don't you want to see me die?
韓某死了不正合三公主心意
Stop your false display of affection.
你何必虛情假意
This...
這
This bamboo tube...
這竹筒
Right.
是啊
Bamboo tube.
竹筒
Someone made a sealing wax bamboo tube
之前有人造了一個火漆竹筒
and tried to frame me for colluding with Xuanhu's spy.
想要構陷韓某與玄虎密探私通
Do you still remember?
三公主可還記得
I'm done for.
完了
You knew it?
你知道了
Why did I say it out?
我 我怎麼 怎麼說出來了
How will you explain it?
對此你作何解釋
Why did you frame me?
你為什麼要陷害我
Why did you lie to me?
要騙我
Don't panic.
你別慌
Let me think about it.
你先讓我想想
I...
我錯
I did it wrong.
錯了
Your Highness,
三公主
even if you did it wrong,
就算咱們做錯了
you can't kneel down.
那也不能跪呀
Girls of Huayuan are dignified.
花垣城女兒膝下有黃金
You can only kneel to Heaven, Earth and Her Majesty.
只能跪天 跪地 跪城主
How can you kneel to your husband?
哪有跪丈夫這一說呀
Get up.
您快起來
My legs are too weak. I can't stand up.
腿軟了 起不來
My legs are weak.
軟 軟了
I really did it wrong.
真 真錯了
I don't understand.
韓某不明白
What did you do wrong?
三公主何錯之有
As for you colluding with Xuanhu's spy,
私會玄虎城密探一事
I made it up.
是我編的
I told Chuchu to catch you,
是我告訴二姐讓她去堵你的
but I really didn't put any defense map
但是我真的沒往那艘船上
on the boat.
放什麼城防圖
I couldn't really get you into trouble.
因為我不能真的害你啊
I know you've known the truth.
我知道你們已經知道真相
I didn't aim to hide you from it,
我也沒打算瞞著你們
or
要不然
I must have long destroyed
這麼明顯的證據
such an obvious evidence.
我早就銷燬了
Right?
是吧
Yes. That's right.
是 是啊
If we aimed to hide you,
我們要是有意瞞你
we couldn't have ordered 500 bamboo tubes.
會做五百個竹筒嗎
Right.
對呀
And we couldn't have placed them in the backyard.
還堂而皇之地放在後院
I'm not stupid.
我傻呀
Five hundred?
五百個
In the backyard?
放後院
That explains how they found it out.
原來是這麼發現的
Come on. You and Bai Ji are really a good match.
真是 跟白芨你倆湊一對得了
Han Shuo,
少君
do you know why I did that?
知道我為什麼要這麼做嗎
Why?
為什麼
I just wanted you
我這不是想讓你
to think highly of me.
對我高看一眼嗎
Since the first time we met,
從少君第一眼見我開始
I've known from your eyes that
我就從你的眼神中
you dislike me.
看出了對我的厭惡
I don't care what other people think of me.
別人怎麼想我 我無所謂
But I don't want you to look down upon me
可是我偏偏不想讓你輕視我
or misunderstand me.
誤會我
I tried to frame you,
我才設計了城防圖一事
just because I wanted to have a chance
我這不是想先
to save you
把你置於險境
after putting you in trouble.
再救你於水火
In this case, you'd change your attitude towards me
這樣你就可以跟我消除隔閡
and trust me more.
更信任我了
Right?
不是嗎
Do you mean
三公主的意思是
you framed me
為了博得韓某歡心
to win my favor?
才故意設計陷害我
You can say that.
可以這麼理解
Colluding with the enemy is a capital crime.
私通敵城是抄家滅族的大罪
How can you do that
怎麼到了三公主嘴裡
to show your affection for me?
就變成對韓某的情根深種了
I'm afraid
此情
I can't afford to bear it.
韓某消受不起
We won't believe you again.
我們不會再相信你了
I know
我知道
I did it in a very stupid way.
雖然我的方法是非常地愚蠢
If you really don't believe me,
但是要是你實在不相信
I'll order them
我就下令
to make fireworks
把剩下的四百九十八個竹筒
with the rest 498 bamboo tubes
全部做成煙花
to show my apology, okay?
給你賠罪行不行
Great.
甚好
What do you mean?
什麼甚好
I mean the moonlight tonight will be great.
我說今晚的月色一定甚好
How about you and me
不如你我
enjoy the glorious moon in the garden?
共赴花園夜宴
And then?
然 然後呢
We can drink some vintage wine.
共飲佳釀
Dear all,
各位祖師爺
here is the story.
現在的情況是這樣的
After knowing that orange made a fool of him,
這香蕉知道橙子之前耍了他
banana changed his mind again and decided to kill her.
於是香蕉對橙子又起了殺心
Is there anything
有沒有什麼辦法
we can do to turn the tide
能夠把這件事情力挽狂瀾一下
so that orange can be saved?
然後 救橙子一命
Orange is really tough.
這橙子生命力還真是頑強啊
I can't believe she's still alive.
居然活到現在
It's because banana is so merciful and kind-hearted
應該是香蕉仁慈 心懷大愛
as to spare her life.
留她到現在
She framed him
栽贓陷害在前
and then deceived him with sweet words.
花言巧語在後
She deserves more than death.
死有餘辜
You can't say that.
話不能這麼說
It's not all orange's fault.
這也不能全怪橙子
She didn't mean it. Right?
她 她也不想啊 對不對
She has a stupid teammate
這不是遇到了豬隊友
who got things wrong.
把事情給弄岔了嗎
Your Highness,
那 那三公主
do you know
這香蕉
what banana's Achilles' heel is?
有沒有什麼致命的弱點呢
He is born with a weak heart.
天生患有心疾
He couldn't live to 20.
活不過二十歲
If orange helps banana get cured,
橙子若是能幫香蕉渡過這個難關
he may give up the idea of killing her.
或許可以讓香蕉放棄殺她的想法
Your Highness,
三公主
when we create a story,
我們寫故事呢
we'll let the protagonists return a favor with a favor.
要以真心換真意
You're nice to him
你對人家好
and he'll pay you back.
人家才能投桃報李
But I'm not a doctor.
可我又不是大夫
There is no medicine that can cure him.
這又沒有治心臟病的藥
How can I get...
我從哪兒去給他
Dragon Bone?
龍骨
Oh, my god.
我的天
One of the main reasons
韓爍假意入贅花垣城的
Han Shuo agreed to marry into Huayuan City
重要原因之一
was to get Dragon Bone
就是為了找到龍骨
and cure himself.
給自己續命
In my original script,
我原來寫到的情節
Chuchu made a lot of preparations to get Dragon Bone for Han Shuo
也是楚楚成為少城主後多方籌劃
after she became the Crown Princess.
才祭出龍骨送給韓爍
Then he began to regard her with special respect.
韓爍這才對她另眼相看的
If I can get Dragon Bone
如果我能拿到龍骨
and cure Han Shuo's heart disease,
治好韓爍的心疾
he's sure to let me go.
他肯定會放過我的
What's wrong?
怎 怎麼了
Your Highness,
三公主啊
Dragon Bone is Huayuan City's most precious treasure.
這龍骨乃是花垣城的鎮城之寶
To stop others casting greedy eyes on it,
為了防止賊人覬覦
only Her Majesty and her successor
全城上下除了城主跟少城主
know where it is.
再無他人知曉
We're just common people.
我等一介草民
We even don't dare to dream of it,
別說把它寫進話本里了
let alone write it down in a story.
就連夢到它都是罪過呀
Dragon Bone can never be used
龍骨是萬萬不可
to cure any disease.
拿來給人治病的呀
Your Highness,
公主
such a thing has never happened before.
歷代城主都沒有此先例呀
It can, because I said so.
我說能它就能
Who am I?
我是誰
I'm the Third Princess who's afraid of nothing.
我是天不怕地不怕的三公主
Get up.
快起來
Your Highness, please think twice.
三公主三思啊
Do you know how to eat a banana?
你們知道這香蕉要怎麼吃嗎
By peeling it.
這 扒皮吃
Exactly. By peeling it.
沒錯 扒著吃
This time, I'll peel him.
這次我一定要扒下他一層皮
How dare he fight a screenwriter?
跟編劇鬥
Let me show you how I'll become a drama queen.
我讓你看看我怎麼給自己加戲
Dragon Bone.
龍骨
Dragon Bone protects Huayuan.
龍骨祕寶 佑我花垣
Dragon Bone...
龍骨祕寶
Enough. Madam. It's annoying.
行了 大姐 煩死了
Your Highness,
三公主
Dragon Bone is Huayuan City's rare treasure.
這龍骨是我花垣城寶物
It's been handed down for generations.
世代相傳
Only Her Majesty and the Crown Princess can touch it.
非城主 少城主不得擅動
I remember it's put here according to the script.
我記得劇本寫的就是在這兒啊
What does it look like?
長什麼樣來著
Could it be...
難道是
Dragon Bone is not here.
龍骨不在這兒
Right. It's not here.
對 不在這兒
Not here?
不在這兒
Stop lying.
騙誰呢
Drop the act.
別裝
Dragon Bone must be here.
這龍骨 指定就在這兒
Your Highness, you can't do this.
三公主不行啊
Your Highness.
三公主啊
Your Highness,
三公主
your mother has told you about this?
這城主連這個都告訴您了
Is it all cut and dried
這少城主擢考還沒舉行
before the Crown Princess Election is held?
這就內定了
Your Highness, stop searching.
三公主 你就別找了
Please, Your Highness.
別找了 三公主
Your Highness, think twice.
三思啊 三公主
Dragon Bone is Huayuan City's most precious treasure.
這龍骨是花垣城鎮城寶
It'll be handed on from age to age.
傳世之寶啊
If you want to touch it,
你要想動它
you must take a bath and burn incense.
須得沐浴焚香
You must also ask the Administration of Heavenly Observatory about a lucky day.
還要請 請司天臺測算吉日吉時
And you need Her Majesty's approval
還要請城主親臨前往
and all officials to be there as eyewitnesses.
眾百官見證才行啊
If
如若呢
Her Majesty doesn't approve
城主不下城主令
or the Administration of Heavenly Observatory can't find a lucky day,
那司天臺不測日子
anyone who touches it will be executed.
要擅動者可是死罪呀
You'll be killed, Your Highness.
是死罪呀 三公主
It...
這
That's the relics...
那 那可是您太 太祖母
Beautiful.
好看好看好看
...found among the cremated ashes of
退位出家
your great-grandmother after she passed away.
圓寂時化成的舍利呀 三公主
Amitabha.
阿彌陀佛 阿彌陀佛
Your Highness.
三公主
I did it wrong.
錯了錯了錯了
It...
這
Your Highness,
三公主啊
this is the colorful coronet used by the first City Owner
這可是第一任城主
when she founded Huayuan City.
建立花垣城時用過的彩冠
It has no equal in this world.
舉世無雙啊
I'm sorry.
對 對不起 對不起
I'll put it back.
我給你插回去 插回去啊
It...
這 這
It's easy. I was too excited.
這很簡單 我一激動
I didn't touch her.
我沒動她
Sorry.
對不起啊
I'm sorry.
真的不好意思
Your Highness.
三公主啊 三公主啊
Your Highness, please spare us.
三公主饒命啊
You can't do that.
可使不得呀
Your Highness.
三公主啊
Dragon Bone?
龍骨
Heaven wants to destroy Huayuan!
天亡花垣
I can't live anymore.
我不活了
I have to die at my post.
我要以身殉職
Don't.
別別別
If I don't die today,
我今天死不了
I'm sure to report it to Her Majesty.
我一定要將此事稟告城主
Don't let her go anywhere.
把她給我看住了
Sorry, madam.
對不起啊 大姐
No wonder they say
難怪傳聞說
the Third Princess can't be entrusted with any important post.
三公主不堪大用
Your Highness, you've got Dragon Bone.
三公主 龍骨找到了
What to do?
怎麼辦
Stew it.
燉它
Okay. Stew it.
好 燉
Stew...
燉 燉
Your Highness, please spare us.
三公主饒命啊
Spare my life.
饒了我吧 饒了我吧
Fine.
行行行
You cowards.
看你們一個個慫的
I won't get you into trouble. I'll do it myself.
不連累你們 我自己來
Heat up water.
燒水
Add star anise to remove the fishy flavor.
八角 大料去腥
Don't, Your Highness.
別呀 公主
Think twice, Your Highness.
三思啊 公主
Why does it stink so much?
這玩意兒怎麼那麼臭
Is it edible?
這能喝嗎
Anyway, we're stewing it.
不過好歹是燉上了
Your Highness.
三公主
Young Master Han has prepared good wine and delicacies.
少君備好了美酒佳餚
He asked me to take you to the garden.
特派屬下請您移步小花園
What will be, will be.
該來的還是來了
Okay.
好
Tell your Young Master
你回去告訴你們少君
I'll...
我馬
I'll be there soon.
我馬上過去
Got it.
是
I tried to show my concern for him,
我本將心向明月
but he wants to kill me.
奈何明月要殺我
Such being the case,
既然如此
get me a chair.
給我搞個椅子過來
What does Her Highness want to do?
三公主究竟要幹什麼呀
Mind your own business.
你管她呢
She even dares to stew Dragon Bone.
她連龍骨都敢燉
There is nothing she doesn't dare to do.
還有什麼她不敢幹
Prop master, is the wine prepared?
道具 酒準備好了嗎
Yes, it is.
早就備好了
As you wish,
按您的吩咐
it's a cup of water. You couldn't get drunk.
白水一杯 包您不醉
Actor, have you recited your lines?
演員 詞背熟了嗎
It's a little long,
字有點多
but I'm good at it.
但我擅長啊
I still need a special effect artist.
現在就差特效
You.
你
Go boil down some syrup.
幫我去熬一點稠一點的糖漿
Make it thicker and redder. Like real blood. Got it?
稠一點 紅一點 逼真一點 明白
Got it.
是
Besides, have the bamboo tubes been remade?
還有 竹筒改造好了嗎
Yes, as you ordered.
按您的吩咐 都改好了
Four hundred and ninety-eight bangs.
四百九十八響
You can count if you don't believe.
不信您數著
Next, it depends on my on-the-spot performance.
接下來就看我的臨場發揮了
Tonight, in the garden,
今晚花園夜宴
do everything at my command.
一切聽我號令
Obey my orders.
聽指揮 聽調度
We have to succeed at one go.
這場戲只能一條過
There is no second chance.
沒有保一條
Got it?
明白
-Got it. -Got it.
是 是
Remember.
都記住了啊
Fireworks will be our signal.
以煙花為號
This time, either we succeed in catching Xuanhu's spy,
此次抓捕玄虎密探
or we die.
不成功 便成仁
Even so, you don't need to risk your life.
那也不用郡主您親自犯險呀
Everything has been set.
已經安排好一切
There is no risk at all.
此事已萬無一失
It's heavily guarded.
我們有重兵把守
Remember.
切記
Without my order,
我若不發令
don't act rashly to give away yourselves.
不可擅動 暴露行蹤
Set out.
出發
Got it.
是
What?
什麼
You can leave.
下去
Why so flustered?
慌什麼
I knew Chuchu
不就是楚楚
had gone to catch Xuanhu's spy.
去抓玄虎密探了嗎
The Third Princess...
三公主
She...
三公主她
What could she do to shock you?
芊芊能出什麼大事
She can just cause some tiny little troubles.
無非是招貓逗狗
There is nothing to be surprised at.
還能反了天不成
The Third Princess...
三 三公主她
She broke into the ancestral hall.
闖進了祖宗的祠堂
Did she tear it down?
她把祠堂拆了
She took Dragon Bone away.
她 她劫了龍骨
She's so disobedient.
這個孽障
I'll hit her to death today.
我今天要活活地打死她
Let's go to Yueli Mansion.
走 去月璃府
Yes, Your Majesty.
是
Han Shuo, sorry for having kept you waiting.
少君 久等了
Han Shuo.
少君
I'll ask you for the last time.
我最後問你一次
I'm feeling a little under the weather.
我今天身體略有不適
Is it okay
我能不能
if I don't drink?
不喝酒了
I took the good wine here from Xuanhu City.
這是我特意從玄虎城帶來的佳釀
It's top-quality.
堪比瓊漿玉液
Have a taste.
三公主嚐嚐
There is no harm in trying it.
喝一杯不礙事
Okay.
好
In this case,
既然如此
you know what I'm like when I get drunk,
你也知道我喝了酒是什麼個德行
so I'll make things clear before we start.
那我得把話說在喝酒之前
I know I'm stupid.
我 自知愚笨
I'm good for nothing.
什麼都做不好
I'm terrible at studying.
讀書也讀不好
I often go to the Music and Dance Academy.
還喜歡去教坊司
My mother often scolded me.
這個母親總是罵我
She said it was difficult to alter my character
說 江山易改 本性難移
and I was hopeless,
說我爛泥扶不上牆
like scrap iron.
就像塊廢鐵
I think you did a good job,
我看你做得挺好的
especially in playing dumb to get what you want.
尤其是扮豬吃虎這一招
It's amazing.
厲害得很
Well. You too.
咱倆 彼此彼此吧
Drinking three cups of wine is a good way to show respect.
喝酒三杯為敬
I'll drink up three cups first.
韓某先敬三杯
Han Shuo, since you came here,
少 少君自從入府以來
you've been having a rough time.
著實辛苦
Actually,
其實自從我
the first time
當日縱馬搶親
I saw you and decided to marry you,
與少君初次見面
I've found that you're in poor health
觀少君面相
by observing your looks.
我就發現你身體不太好
After these days we spent together,
又經過多日的相處
I found out
發覺少君
you had always been bothered by your heart disease.
是因為心疾所困
It makes me quite worried.
這讓我非常揪心啊
Don't.
別 別 別
I haven't finished my words.
話 話還沒說完
Han Shuo,
少君
I know I did a lot of things wrong,
我知道我做了很多錯事
but I was forced to.
但我真的是逼不得已的
You're so broad-minded and generous
少君寬宏大量
that you've forgiven me,
大人不計小人過
but I still feel very guilty deep inside.
但是我的內心已經愧疚不已了
As the saying goes,
俗話說得好
one day together as husband and wife means endless devotion the rest of your life.
一日夫妻百日恩
A couple is a team.
咱倆夫妻一體
I'll definitely think about your interests
所有事情
no matter what I do.
我自當是為少君考慮的
So,
所以今日
I've got you
我特地為少君
a guiding drug
求得一位藥引
to make sure you can be cured
想要少君長命百歲
and the two of us will live together until old age.
和我白頭偕老
To cure my disease,
想要治癒我的病
you have to get one thing.
只有一味藥
Do you know what it is?
你可知道
Dragon Bone.
龍骨
I've got it for you.
我都給你拿來了
You must be joking.
三公主說笑了
Dragon Bone is so precious.
龍骨是何等祕寶
How could you get it so easily?
怎會說拿就拿
You don't believe?
你不信
In this case,
你要是不信
you can go have a look in the kitchen.
你去小院的後廚看看
It's being stewed.
我都燉上了
Based on the cooking time,
算算時間的話
I think it's almost ready.
也差不多要燉好了
If you're interested,
你要是有興趣的話
you can also smell it.
你還可以 聞一聞
Young Master,
少君
a pot of water turns into a bowl of soup.
一鍋水熬成一碗湯
All the essence is condensed here.
濃縮的千年精華呀
Dragon Bone
你說這龍骨
is Huayuan City's most precious treasure.
乃花垣城的鎮城之寶
Did Chen Qianqian really get it for our Young Master?
三公主當真為我們少君求得龍骨
Of course.
當然了
It's absolutely true.
這龍骨還能有假呀
Legend has it that
傳說
the first City Owner of Huayuan
花垣城第一任城主
found this medicinal material by accident.
是偶然之間發現了這味藥材
It can remove all poison and cure all disease.
可解百毒 可治百病
It's considered as an auspicious sign and named Dragon Bone.
視為祥瑞 取名龍骨
The founder of Huayuan got Dragon Bone
開城城主是先得龍骨
and then the black stone mine
後得烏石礦
before she founded the city.
而後立城
Every City Owner of Huayuan believes
歷代花垣城的城主都堅信著
the city is safe because of Dragon Bone
龍骨保佑著花垣城
and the city develops because of the mine.
烏石礦養活了花垣城
You can keep exploiting the mine,
礦 可以不斷開採
but there is only one piece of Dragon Bone.
這龍骨 只有一塊呀
Don't you think it's precious?
你說 珍貴不珍貴
Stop bragging.
你咋那麼能吹呢
Pitifully,
只是可惜了啊
the Third Princess has stewed Dragon Bone
我們三公主燉了龍骨
so that Young Master Han can get cured,
你們家那少君的心疾是治好了
but what will she do
那城主怪罪下來
when her mother blames her
這我們三公主
for doing that?
這罪過怎麼辦呀
The smell explains why it's most precious.
這味道不愧是千年祕寶啊
Is Chen Qianqian really so nice to me?
三公主真會這麼好心
Young Master, she's still in the garden.
少君 小花園
Damn.
糟了
The terrain is open ahead.
前方地勢開闊
Let's branch out into two columns.
我們兵分兩路
Launch a converging attack when you see fireworks.
以煙花為號 前後夾擊
Be careful.
千萬小心
Don't let them find us and escape.
別被他們發現 讓他們逃走
Got it.
是
Want to fight me?
跟我鬥
Now that you're a character in a script,
你活在劇本里
the screenwriter has the final say.
這編劇就是天
Even if you force me into a corner,
就算你把我逼到了絕路
I can still
我也可以
turn things around.
可以起死回生
Qianqian, no!
芊芊不要
Qianqian.
芊芊
Han Shuo.
少君
The wine is poisoned. Don't drink it.
酒 酒裡有毒 你別喝
Be careful!
大家小心
Qianqian. Qianqian.
芊芊 芊芊
Qianqian.
芊芊
Chen Qianqian, don't die!
陳芊芊 我不許你死
Hurry up.
快點 快點
Hurry.
快走 快走
(Yueli Mansion)
快快快
Your Majesty.
城主
Why did I have such a disobedient daughter?
我怎麼生了這個孽障
Go to the kitchen.
快 去廚房
Yes, Your Majesty.
是
Can you get Dragon Bone out?
龍骨還能撈出來嗎
Please spare my life.
城主饒命
It's melted.
龍骨都化了
The Third Princess ordered us to do it.
我們是聽了三公主的命令才燉的
What a disobedient girl.
這個孽障
I'll beat her to death,
今天我不打死她
or I don't deserve to be the City Owner.
我枉為城主
Your Majesty.
城主
Your Majesty, the Third Princess is poisoned.
稟告城主 三公主身中奇毒
What?
什麼
How is she doing?
人怎麼樣了
I'm not sure if she's alive or not.
生死不知
It...
這
Your Majesty, don't panic.
城主莫慌
Dragon Bone can remove all poison and cure all disease.
這龍骨 可解百毒 治百病
Send for Yuanyuan.
去請沅沅
Yes, Your Majesty.
是
Sangqi,
桑奇
take Dragon Bone and follow me.
帶上龍骨 快走
Yes, Your Majesty.
是
You good-for-nothings.
一群廢物
Your Highness, what do you think?
大郡主 你怎麼看
I don't think it's fatal.
應該是與性命無礙
As for the rest,
但別的
I'm not sure.
我摸不出來
Hurry. Take Dragon Bone here.
快 先把龍骨端上來
Young Master.
少君
Han Shuo,
韓爍
Dragon Bone is Huayuan City's most precious treasure.
龍骨乃花垣城祕寶
It can remove all poison and cure all disease.
可治百病 可解百毒
There has been only one piece in the past 1,000 years.
千年來 只此一根
I see.
韓某知道
Qianqian got it for you
芊芊是冒了殺頭之罪
at the risk of her life.
為你取來的
Won't you take it
你不喝下去
to cure your heart disease?
治療你的心疾嗎
She has done so much for me.
她為我做了這麼多
I can't let her die like this.
我不能讓她就這麼死了
As I said, the Third Princess is alright.
我就說三公主沒事吧
Dragon Bone deserves its reputation.
果然是龍骨
It works like a charm.
藥到病除
Maybe I'm not seriously poisoned,
許是我中毒不深
so I get better with only one sip.
一口就好了
Han Shuo,
少君
it can cure your heart disease.
這龍骨 能治癒你的心疾
Take it.
你趕緊
It took me so much effort
我千辛萬苦
to get Dragon Bone,
為你偷來了龍骨
but you're not grateful at all.
你竟然如此怠慢
Take it now.
你趕緊喝了呀你
I don't dare to.
韓某不敢
My only wish
我唯一的心願
is to cure your heart disease.
就是為你治心疾
If you don't take it,
如今你不喝
I'll be heartbroken. I feel dizzy. I want to die.
那我就心痛難忍 頭暈 我想死
Your Highness, calm down.
三公主莫要激動
Anxiety is bad for your health.
激動傷身
Take it.
你趕緊喝了吧
She's threatening you with her own life.
她這是以命相逼呢
Under the circumstances...
事到如今
I know.
我知道
I know I let you down
知道竹筒的事情
because of the bamboo tube thing.
是我對不起你
I feel guilty of you.
我知道我有愧於你
When you had heart attacks that day...
但是那日看你突發心疾
I don't have the heart to see you suffer.
我於心不忍
Drink the Dragon Bone soup.
就把這龍骨喝了吧
Drink it immediately.
你快點喝
Otherwise, it will become stinkier when it's cold.
再不喝涼了就更臭了都得
How are you feeling?
怎麼樣
Are you feeling full of energy?
有沒有感覺渾身上下充滿了力量
I'm not feeling anything special.
倒是沒有什麼特別的感覺
It's just...
只是
You've taken Dragon Bone.
你喝了龍骨
Your heart disease will be cured.
就能治好你的心疾了
You're sure to recover
少君喝了龍骨
after taking Dragon Bone.
定能痊癒的
In this case,
這樣
I'll
我也就
be relieved.
放 心 了
Hurry.
快快快 快
Mother?
母 母親
Qianqian, you're really awake?
芊芊 你真的醒了
Mother, I'm fine.
母親 我沒事了
Go back and rest up.
你趕緊回去休息吧
Qianqian,
芊芊啊
you're feeling sorry for me now?
你現在知道體恤母親了
Why didn't you think about me
燉龍骨的時候
when you decided to stew Dragon Bone?
你怎麼就不替我想想呢
It has been handed down for so many generations,
傳了多少代的龍骨
but now it's destroyed.
毀在我手裡了
How should I explain to my ancestors?
我怎麼向列祖列宗交代呀
How could the common people and officials
花垣城的百姓和官員們
let you go?
怎麼會放過你呢
Mother, I did it wrong. I'm sorry.
母親 我錯了 對不起
Your Majesty.
城主
Take it.
來
Mother.
母親
Don't be afraid.
不怕
You've just stewed one piece of Dragon Bone.
不就是燉了一根龍骨嗎
I'll protect you.
我會保護你的
As long as I'm here,
只要有我在呀
nobody can hurt you.
我不會讓任何人傷害到你
Alright. Take it.
好 來 喝吧
Here.
來